别怕
Easy.
来的路上看到了几只火鸡
Saw some turkeys on the way here.
大摇大摆地走过我面前  当我不存在
Crossed right in front of me like I wasn't even there.
太放肆了
How rude of them.
还不是因为
That's what happens when you
连着六天下矿干活
spend six days a week working in the mines.
蠢鸟们都以为林子是它们家的了
Stupid birds start to think they own these woods.
什么时候出发
When's the tour leave?
几个小时以后
Couple hours.
我们走吧
Well, let's go.
-没事的  -放开我
- Hey. You're okay. - Let go!
没事  你很安全
You're okay. You're safe.
别怕  有我在呢
It's okay. You're here with me.
有我呢
You're with me.
别怕  别怕
Okay, okay.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们...
We should...
我们回去吧
We should go.
禁
止
穿
越
你会来车站送我吗
Are you coming to the train station?
送你的人够多了
I think you have enough people saying goodbye without me there.
但没几个我在乎的
Only a few I actually care about.
不去送你反而轻松些
It might be easier if I didn't.
几周而已
It's only a few weeks.
没等雪融化  我就能回来了
I'll be back before the snow melts.
几周的时间能发生很多事
A lot can happen in a few weeks.
还要我再解释一遍吗
Are we gonna do this again?
盖尔  那只是演戏
Gale, it was an act.
是啊  演得像真的似的
Yeah, it was a good one.
为了生存我不得不演  不然我早就死了
I did what I had to do to survive. If I didn't, I'd be dead.
我也不得不吻
I had to do that.
至少得吻一次
At least once.
胜利者村
海米奇
Haymitch!
海米奇  起来  今天要开始巡演了
Haymitch, wake up. It's Tour Day.
海米奇
Haymitch.
你搞什么
What are you doing?
还有一小时  摄像机就来了
Cameras are gonna be here in an hour.
想让人宠着你  找皮塔去
If you wanted to be babied, you should've asked Peeta.
找我什么事
Asked me what?
找你叫醒我  而不是害我得肺炎
Asked you to wake me without giving me pneumonia.
你真是个讨人厌的奇葩
You are a strangely dislikeable person.
但也有优点
But you do have your virtues.
来点面包吗  凯妮丝
Would you like some bread, Katniss?
不  我在霍布吃过了  谢谢
No, I ate at the Hob, but thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
上节目前你俩可得好好磨合一下
You two have a lot of warming up to do before show time.
还有一小时了  冲个澡吧  海米奇
Which is in an hour, so take a bath, Haymitch.
刚被冲过了
I just did.
散步怎么样  亲爱的
Did you have a good walk, dear?
散步?  我刚才是去
Walk? I was just out...
有人来看你
We have visitors.
艾佛丁小姐  这边请
Miss Everdeen. This way, please.
真勇敢
Such bravery.
真有气魄
Such spirit.
真是
Such...
蔑视权力
Contempt.
斯诺总统
President Snow.
很荣幸见到您
What an honor.
亲爱的  我们都直话直说吧
My dear, I think we can make this so much simpler
这样更容易  你觉得呢
if we agree not to lie to each other. What do you think?
没错  这样更省时间
Yes, I think that would save time.
请坐
Sit down, please.
我有个问题  艾佛丁小姐
I have a problem, Miss Everdeen.
问题源起于
A problem that began the moment
你在竞技场拿出了毒浆果
you revealed those poison berries in the arena.
前总设计师希尼卡·克莱恩要是有脑子
If that Head Gamemaker, Seneca Crane, had had any brains at all,
当时就该炸得你们俩灰飞烟灭
he would have blown you to bits then and there.
但是你还在
But here you are.
你也应该能猜到他是什么下场
I expect you can guess where he is.
是的  猜到了
Yes, I think so.
那次失误后  我也没办法
After that fiasco, there was nothing left to do
只能看你自导自演
but to let you play out your little scenario.
你演得还不错
And you were very good.
为爱冲昏头脑的小女生那一套
That whole love-crazed, besotted schoolgirl routine.
演得好  真的
Impressive. Truly.
你让都城人深信不疑
You convinced the people in The Capitol.
不幸的是  不是每个人都信你那一套
Unfortunately, not everyone in the districts fell for it.
你不知道  有几个区的人
I mean, you can't know this, but in several of them,
把你拿毒浆果的小把戏
people viewed your little trick with the berries
当成了挑衅
as an act of defiance.
而不是出于爱情
Not as an act of love.
如果一个12区的一个小毛孩子
And if a girl from District 12 of all places
敢挑衅都城  居然还毫发无损
can defy The Capitol and walk away unharmed,
还怎么管理其他人
what is to prevent them from doing the same?
怎么阻止  比如说  暴动
What is to prevent, say, an uprising?
那就可能引起革命
That can lead to revolution.
一不小心  整个社会体系都会土崩瓦解
And then, in a fraction of time, the whole system collapses.
如果几颗浆果就能摧毁这个体系
It must be a fragile system,
那它可真是脆弱
if it can be brought down by just a few berries.
没错  确实是
Yes, it is, indeed.
但不像你想象的那样
But not in the way you imagine it.
那该怎么想象
How should I imagine?
想象成千上万的平民会死掉
You should imagine thousands upon thousands of your people dead.
你的家乡会土崩瓦解
This town of yours reduced to ashes.
想象一下它被夷为平地
Imagine it gone.
被核污染
Made radioactive.
深埋于地下  不复存在  就像13区
Buried under dirt as if it had never existed, like District 13.
你在比赛里很英勇  艾佛丁小姐
You fought very hard in The Games, Miss Everdeen.
但那终究是场游戏
But they were games.
你想触发一场真的战争吗
Would you like to be in a real war?
不想
No.
很好  我也不想
Good. Neither would I.
你妈妈做的吗
Did your mother make these?
是皮塔
Peeta.
多好的小伙子
He's a lovely boy.
告诉我
Tell me.
他有意识到
At what point did he realize
你对他的冷淡吗
the depth of your indifference towards him?
我并不冷淡
I'm not indifferent.
别撒谎
Don't lie!
你答应过的
You promised.
你怎么不杀了我
Why don't you just kill me now?
我不想杀了你
I don't want to kill you.
我想和你做朋友
I want us to be friends.
即使不是朋友  也是同盟
But if not friends, then allies.
你要我怎么做
What do I need to do?
你和皮塔巡演的时候
When you and Peeta are on tour,
你要微笑  要感恩
you need to smile. You need to be grateful.
最重要的是  你们要疯狂地
But, above all, you need to be madly,
不顾一切地相爱
prepared-to-end-it-all in love.
-你能做到吗  -能做到
- You think you can manage that? - Yes.
能做到什么
Yes, what?
-我会让他们信服  -不对
- I'll convince them. - No.
是让我信服
Convince me.
送给你  艾佛丁小姐
For you, Miss Everdeen.
你要让我信服
Do convince me.
为了你爱的人
For the sake of your loved ones.
停下
Stop.
感受一下
Take it all in.
这片神圣的土地
This is sacred ground.
这里创造过辉煌历史
History was made here.
你们会慢慢习惯这臭味的
You'll get used to the smell.
你好
Hello!
她在这  伟大的冠军
There she is. My greatest triumph!
我们的大明星
Our little superstar.
亲爱的  我们好想你
Sweetie, we've missed you.
多可爱的房子
What a cute little house.
多古雅  不是吗
So quaint, isn't it?
你肯定听说秦纳的事了吧
Of course, you've heard about Cinna?
秦纳怎么了
What happened to Cinna?
亲爱的  他现在可是时尚界巨星
Oh, dear, he's a fashion star.
而你是他的灵感
You're his muse.
都城人都穿戴他设计的  人人都是
Everyone in The Capitol's wearing him. Everyone.
-每个人都穿  -也不是每个人
- Everyone. - Well, not everyone.
秦纳
Cinna!
凯妮丝
Katniss?
凯妮丝  这是你妹妹吗
Katniss, is this your sister?
亲爱的
Oh, sweetie!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
好可爱
Just adorable!
-没事  -准备好了吗
- Yeah. - Ready to work?
-好了  -很好
- Yeah. - All right. Good.
欢迎大家
Welcome!
去年  第74届饥饿游戏
Last year, the 74th Hunger Games
促成了一段爱情佳话
brought us the greatest love story of our time.
两个勇敢的年轻人  历尽艰辛
Two brave young people, against all odds,
宁死也不愿失去彼此
chose to die rather than to lose each other.
而我们  见证了他们的痛苦
As a nation, we shared their agony.
却没来得及分享他们的喜悦
But we had so little time to revel in their joy.
是时候了
It's time!
妆好了  很美了  惊艳全场吧
She's done, she's lovely. We must feed the monster.
好了
All right now.
让我们走进12区  看看这对苦命鸳鸯
Let's go to District 12 and find our star-crossed lovers!
你很兴奋  你正热恋
You're excited. You're in love.
来个灿烂的微笑  倒数三  二  一
Big smiles for the camera in three, two, one.
她来了  凯妮丝·艾佛丁
There she is! Katniss Everdeen!
燃烧的女孩
The Girl on Fire.
他也来了  皮塔·梅尔拉克
And there he is! Peeta Mellark!
面包师家的男孩
The Baker's Boy.
甜蜜的一摔
Trouble in paradise.
但愿他们没事
I hope they're all right.
有人吗  不然我们回避一下吧
Anyone at home? Should we come back later?
抱歉  凯撒
Sorry, Caesar.
没关系  你说的算
Please. It's all right. It's your day.
你说的算  最近怎么样
It's your day. So how's it going?
我们很好
We're good.
没别的吗  就一句"我们很好"
That's it? That's all we get? "We're good?"
怎么突然沉默寡言了
So taciturn all of a sudden.
皮塔  详细说说
Peeta, give me some details!
12区的日子不错
Yeah, things are great here in 12.
多亏慷慨的都城
Thanks to the generosity of The Capitol,
让我们无比亲近
we've never been closer.
只隔了25码
Twenty-five yards, to be exact.
说得好
Fantastic!
胜利巡演的时候
We'll be checking in with
我们再聊
both of you throughout the Victory Tour.
感谢你们
Thank you so much,
凯妮丝·艾佛丁和皮塔·梅尔拉克
Katniss Everdeen and Peeta Mellark!
太棒了
Wonderful!
大家都准备好  10分钟后出发
Everybody in motion. We are out of here in 10.
-演得很好  -你也是
- That was nice acting. - You, too.
那个吻都快让我信以为真了
Almost thought that kiss was real.
快走  孩子们  时间快到了
Come along, children, we are on a schedule.
火车等着呢
The train awaits!
美食  美酒  按摩  温泉
Fabulous food, fabulous wine, the massages, spa treatments.
我吩咐过  要给我们的冠军最好的享受
I told them nothing but the best for my two Victors.
一切都要...
It all needs to be...
完美无瑕
Fabulous?
正是
Exactly.
计划有点紧  12天  12个区
Now, the schedule is a bit of a bear. 12 days, 12 districts.
但每一站都是些派对  庆典
But it's mostly parties, celebrations,
可爱粉丝们的祝贺
adoring fans to greet you at every stop along the way,
最后抵达都城
and then we wrap it up in The Capitol.
只要你讲讲话  挥挥手
All you need to do is give a few speeches, wave to the crowds,
好好享受众星捧月的感觉
and enjoy your time in the spotlight.
这是你应得的
You've earned it.
你说什么
What did you say?
凯妮丝
Katniss.
我说  好好享受  这是你应得的
I said, "Enjoy it, Katniss, you've earned it."
通过杀人得来的
By killing people.
姑娘
Young lady...
我现在没心情听大道理
I'm really not in the mood for a lecture.
我一会再像艾菲道歉
I'll apologize to Effie later.
我还以为是海米奇
I thought you were Haymitch.
你不用向谁道歉
You don't have to apologize to anybody.
包括我
Including me.
我知道我不应该
I know it's not fair of me
抓住你在比赛里说的话不放
to hold you to things you said in The Games.
你救了我们俩  我知道
You saved us. I know that.
但是我没法在镜头前秀恩爱
But I can't go on acting for the cameras,
现实里却假装是路人
and then just ignoring each other in real life.
如果你把我当伤者看待
So if you can stop looking at me like I'm wounded,
我也就不用假装受伤了
then I can quit acting like it.
也许我们还有机会做朋友
And then maybe we have a shot at being friends.
我不太会交朋友
I've never been very good at friends.
交朋友能帮你了解一个人
For starters, it does help when you know the person.
我对你差不多一无所知
I hardly know anything about you
只知道你脾气倔  会射箭
except that you're stubborn and good with a bow.
差不多说全了
That about sums me up.
不  不止这些  你只是不想说
No, there's more than that, you just don't want to tell me.
我说了  我...
It's like I said, I'm...
凯妮丝  要想交朋友
See, Katniss, the way the whole friend thing works
就得敞开心扉
is you have to tell each other the deep stuff.
-敞开心扉  -是的
- The deep stuff? - Yeah.
说点什么
Like what?
比如
Like...
你最喜欢什么颜色
What's your favorite color?
这问题太过分了
Well, now you've stepped over the line.
不开玩笑  什么颜色
Seriously, though, what is it?
绿色
Green.
你的呢
What's yours?
橙色
Orange.
艾菲头发的颜色吗
Like Effie's hair?
不  没那么橙
No. Not that orange.
是日落的那种橙色
More like a sunset kind of orange.
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
什么
What?
真没想到
Well, I never.
这的气氛不对
This is not very festive.
市长先来段开场白
The mayor will make some introductory remarks.
然后你们只要简单说几句
And then you just have to say a few words.
通常就是
It's customary, of course,
先悼念一下本区逝去的贡品
to give a brief eulogy to the district's fallen Tributes.
11区的是瑟莱仕和芸香
For 11, that's Thresh and Rue.
这是演讲词
Here are the speeches.
我可以替你说
I can do the talking if you want.
谢谢
Thank you.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎第74届饥饿游戏冠军
the Victors of the 74th Hunger Games.
凯妮丝·艾佛丁和皮塔·梅尔拉克
Katniss Everdeen and Peeta Mellark!
微笑  微笑
Smile, smile, smile, smile.
昂首挺胸  你要上镜了
Stand up straight. You're on camera.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
很荣幸见到大家
We're honored to be here with you today.
见到已故贡品的家人
And to be with the families of your fallen Tributes.
他放下了卡片
He put down the cards.
他们为荣誉和尊严而战
Though they fought and lived with honor...
关我什么事
Why do I bother?
直到最后
..and dignity until the end,
瑟莱仕和芸香
both Thresh and Rue
都还那么年轻
were so young.
但生命不能用时间来衡量
But our lives aren't just measured in years.
而要看你对他人的影响
They're measured in the lives of people we touch around us.
对于我
For myself,
对于凯妮丝
for Katniss,
我们都知道  如果没有芸香和瑟莱仕
we know that without Rue and without Thresh,
我们也不可能有今天
we wouldn't be standing here today.
为了表达我们的感激之情
So in recognition of that,
虽然无法慰藉丧亲之痛
knowing that it in no way can make up for your loss,
我们还是想向贡品的家人
we'd like to donate one month
捐赠我们一个月的奖金
of our winnings to the families of the Tributes,
从今以后  年年如此
every year, for the rest of our lives.
糟糕
Shit.
他能这么做吗
Can he do that?
不能  但还是承诺了
He can't. But he did.
为什么不念卡片呢
Why doesn't he just stick to the cards?
谢谢
Thank you.
我想说  我并不了解瑟莱仕
I just wanted to say that I didn't know Thresh.
只和他说过一次话
I only spoke to him once.
他本可以杀了我  但却放我一条生路
He could have killed me, but instead he showed me mercy.
他的恩情我永远报答不完
That's a debt I'll never be able to repay.
我很了解芸香
I did know Rue.
她不仅仅是我的盟友  更是我的朋友
She wasn't just my ally, she was my friend.
我在屋边草地里的小花上
I see her in the flowers
能看到她的身影
that grow in the meadow by my house.
嘲笑鸟的歌声中似乎有她的声音
I hear her in a Mockingjay song.
我妹妹身上也有她的影子
I see her in my sister Prim.
她还太小
She was too young,
太柔弱
too gentle.
我没能救下她
And I couldn't save her.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不  不
No! No!
等等  等等
Wait! Wait!
不  别抓他  别抓他
No! Leave him alone! Leave him alone!
不  放开我  别抓他
No! Let me go! Please leave him alone!
不
No!
你  不  不
You! No, no, no!
过来  别动
Come here! Stop it!
别动  别动
Stop it! Stop!
我做了什么啊
What did I do?
过来
Come on.
别喊
Shut up.
活了这么多年  我还从没见过...
In all my years, I've never seen...
这么简单的事都做不好
You two have a very simple task.
我没想到会出人命  他得知道
I never meant for anyone to get killed. He has to know that.
你说什么  谁得知道
What are you talking about? Who has to know what?
斯诺  他来看过我
Snow. He came to see me.
他担心各区会反叛
He's worried about rebellion in the districts.
他觉得他们不相信我们的爱情故事
He thinks that they don't believe our love story.
所以他要让他们信服
So he wants you to make them believe it?
-平息反叛情绪  -凯妮丝
- To calm things down. - You know, Katniss,
你应该在我出去之前
you shoulda told me that before I went out there,
在我给他们钱之前就告诉我的
and tried to give these people the money.
对不起  我不知道该怎么办
I'm sorry. I didn't know what to do.
他威胁说要杀了我家人
He threatened to kill my family.
我也有家人
Well, I have family, too.
知道吗  我也有要保护的人
Okay? People that I need to protect.
他们怎么办  谁保护他们
What about them? Who protects them?
凯妮丝  你怎么想的
Katniss, what were you thinking?
我满脑子都是芸香
I was thinking about Rue.
海米奇  拜托你
Haymitch, please...
求你了  帮我度过这次旅程吧
Please, just help me get through this trip.
求你了  帮帮我们
Please, just help us get through this.
这次旅程?  醒醒吧  孩子
This trip? Girl, wake up.
这次旅程不会因你回到家就结束
This trip doesn't end when you get back home.
上了这趟车就没有回头路了
You never get off this train.
你们俩现在是导师
You two are mentors now.
就是说每年你们都要露面
That means that every year, they're gonna drag you out,
讲你们俩的罗曼史
and broadcast the details of your romance.
你们的私生活都是他们的谈资
Every year, your private life becomes theirs.
从现在起  你们要分散公众的注意力
From now on, your job is to be a distraction.
不要让他们看到真正的问题
So people forget what the real problems are.
-我们要怎么做  -要微笑
- So what do we do? - You're gonna smile.
要照着艾菲给你们的演讲稿念
You're gonna read the cards that Effie gives you.
要永远幸福地生活在一起
And you're gonna live happily ever after.
能做到吗
Think you can do that?
真的吗
Yeah?
过来
Come here.
你们会没事的  我保证
You're gonna be okay. I promise.
凯妮丝和我想跟你们分享胜利的喜悦
Katniss and I want to share with you our victory.
感谢都城让我们相遇相知
And our gratitude to The Capitol for bringing us together.
严酷的比赛是我们爱的纽带
It was the bond of love, forged in the crucible of The Games
这份爱是我们最大的收获
that was our greatest prize.
是真爱
For it is love and true love
让我们战胜了一切困难
that allows us all to bear our hardships.
抚慰心灵  驱赶孤独
That mends the heart and banishes loneliness
让我们的人生有了意义
and gives meaning to our lives.
同时也对逝者的离去感到悲痛不已
We also want to share with you the sorrows of your losses.
这个区的贡品...
The Tributes of this...
这个区的贡品都是勇敢杰出的勇士
The Tributes of this district were brave and noble warriors.
不仅给家人带来荣耀
They brought honor to their families,
更令人民感到自豪
and pride to their people.
大家团结一致
We are all of us united,
不管是冠军或是战败者
both victors and vanquished,
都效忠于共同的目标
in serving a common purpose.
谢谢
Thank you.
总有一天我也要跟你一样  去做志愿者
One day, I'm gonna volunteer. Just like you did.
做噩梦而已  抱歉
It was just a dream. I'm sorry.
没事  我也会做噩梦
It's okay. I get 'em, too.
晚安
Goodnight.
皮塔
Peeta.
能陪着我吗
Will you stay with me?
好的
Yeah.
永远
Always.
大家团结一致
We are all of us united,
不管是冠军还是战败者
both victors and vanquished,
好运永不与我们同在
都效忠于共同的目标
in serving a common purpose.
都城的权力与荣耀
The power and glory of The Capitol.
把卡片放下
Put down the cards!
说出你的真实想法
Tell us what you really think!
施惠国长存  施惠国万岁
Panem today. Panem tomorrow. Panem forever.
你的发型很好看  亲爱的
Your hair looks lovely, darling.
什么时候开始弄的
When did you start wearing it like that?
爷爷  现在学校里人人都扎这头发
Everyone at school wears it like this now, Grandpa.
斯诺正看着我们
Snow is watching us.
他想让你们安抚各区情绪吗
If he wants you to pacify the districts,
那他现在肯定不高兴
I promise you, he's not happy.
比起相爱
Instead of being in love,
你们俩更像是在背钻油指南
you two sound like you're reciting from a drilling manual.
你试试去读艾菲给我们写的东西啊
You try reading that stuff that Effie writes us.
这话2天后你自己去跟斯诺总统说
Tell that to President Snow when you see him two days from now.
那我洗耳恭听
I'm open to suggestions.
我们可以结婚
We could get married.
一点都不好笑
That's not helping.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
要是像你说的  我们无法回头了
If, like you said, we're on this train forever,
结婚是迟早的事
it's gonna happen eventually.
何不现在结
Why not now?
结婚倒是可以表明立场
It does make a statement. I'll give you that.
是啊  结就结吧
Yeah, sure. Let's do it.
你是不是还在为
Just when you thought things
精英极限赛而激动呢  更激动人心的来了
couldn't get more exciting going into a very special Quarter Quell,
这对来自12区的致命恋人
our two lethal lovers, my favorite expression,
我最喜爱的称呼
from District 12,
又有了新的动向
have surprised us with a new twist in their love affair.
让我们来看一看
Let's take a look.
这对不幸的恋人要执手偕老了
A fairy tale ending for two star-crossed lovers.
真是太美  太美了
That's beautiful. Beautiful.
而今晚
And then tonight,
这场在12区山谷开始的旅程
the tour that began in the hollows of District 12
将在哪里结束
will end where?
总统官邸
The Presidential Palace.
年度盛典
The party of the year.
眼睛放光  抬起头来  保持微笑
Eyes bright. Chins up. Smiles on.
我说你呢  凯妮丝
I'm talking to you, Katniss.
从现在起将会有摄影师和记者围住你们
Now, there'll be photographers. Interviews.
大家都会来祝贺你们
Everyone will be here to celebrate you.
我的冠军
My Victors.
好好感受吧  孩子们
Breathe it all in, children.
都是为你们准备的
This is all for you.
饱而思淫欲
It's cozy.
注意态度
Attitude.
来  来
Come, come.
快过来
Come along.
抱歉  抱歉
Excuse us, excuse us.
来  来
Come, come.
牵手
Hold hands.
这里是藏书室  全是红木的
And the library. All mahogany.
你好  你好
Hello, hello!
等会儿  等会儿  还不行
Not yet, not yet. No, no, no.
是挂帘
Curtains!
有名望的人今晚都到了
Everybody who's anybody is here.
都想见你们
And they all want to meet you.
弗拉维斯  奥科塔娅
Flavius! Octavia!
再尝尝这个  人间美味
Try one of these. They are divine.
不  我吃不下了
No, I can't eat another thing.
-给  -这是什么
- Here. - What's this?
给你吃不下的时候喝的
It's for when you're full.
能让你呕吐
It makes you sick.
这样就能接着吃了
So you can go on eating.
不然怎么能尝尽所有美食
How else could you taste everything?
还是跳支舞吧
I think it's time for a dance.
凯妮丝
Katniss?
12区的人正在挨饿
People are starving in 12.
而他们却为了吃更多而把食物吐出来
Here, they're just throwing it up to stuff more in.
凯妮丝  皮塔
Katniss? Peeta.
这位是普鲁塔什·海文斯比
This is Plutarch Heavensbee.
总设计师
Head Gamemaker.
希尼卡·克莱恩的继任者
Successor to Seneca Crane.
可千万别学他
That's a tough act to follow.
皮塔
Peeta!
可以邀她共舞吗
May I?
请吧
Please.
喜欢这派对吗
So how do you like the party?
有点太过了
It's a little overwhelming.
有点恶心
It's appalling.
如果你不装清高  还是挺好玩的
Still, if you abandon your moral judgment, it can be fun.
你觉得好玩吗
So are you having fun?
我是总设计师  当然得觉得好玩
I'm the Head Gamemaker. Fun is my job.
想必希尼卡·克莱恩也是这样子
Thought that was what happened to Seneca Crane.
玩太过了
Too much fun.
希尼卡是自寻死路
Seneca decided to quit breathing.
自寻
Decided.
要不然就是毒浆果害的
It was that or poison berries.
当总设计师
Being Head Gamemaker has never been
就要承担相应的风险
the most secure job in the world.
那为什么你还要当
Then why are you here?
跟你一样  我自愿的
Same reason as you. I volunteered.
为什么
Why?
因为野心
Ambition.
让比赛变得有意义
The chance to make The Games mean something.
这比赛没有意义
The Games don't mean anything.
只能使我们感到害怕
They only mean to scare us.
也许是受你启发  我才回来
Well, maybe it was you who inspired me to come back.
总统欢迎仪式
The Presidential welcome.
我们会再见的
I'm sure we'll meet again.
凯妮丝  快来  总统在等着呢
Katniss, come. The President awaits.
咱俩做的能说服他吗
You think we convinced him?
反正已经尽力了
I'm not sure what else we can do.
今晚  在他们旅程的最后一天
Tonight, on this, the last day of their tour,
我想要向这两位冠军致意
I want to welcome our two Victors.
两位实力与英勇并存的年轻典范
Two young people who embody our ideals of strength and valor.
在此我想为他们的婚约
And I, personally, want to congratulate them
送上我诚挚的祝福
on the announcement of their engagement.
这份爱激励着我们
Your love has inspired us.
而你们多活一天
And I know it will go on inspiring us
就能多激励我们一天
everyday for as long as you may live.
看看他们
Look at them.
她不是他们想要找的人
She's not who they think she is.
她不是个领袖
She's not a leader.
她只想顾全自己  就是这么简单
She just wants to save her own skin. It's as simple as that.
你说得对
I think that's true.
可是她却成为了反抗的希望
But she's become a beacon of hope for the rebellion.
必须除掉她
And she has to be eliminated.
她是得死  不过要以正确的方式
I agree she should die. But in the right way.
在正确的时间
At the right time.
每一步
It's moves and countermoves.
都要仔细设计
That's all we gotta look at.
凯妮丝·艾佛丁象征着他们的嘲笑鸟
Katniss Everdeen is a symbol. Their Mockingjay.
反抗者以为她是一伙的
They think she's one of them.
我们得向众人展示她是我们这边的
We need to show that she's one of us.
不用杀她  毁了她的形象
We don't need to destroy her. Just the image.
让民众自己动手
Then we let the people do the rest.
有什么好建议
What do you propose?
端掉黑市  一点都不剩
Shut down the black markets. Take away what little they have.
把鞭刑和死刑的数量加倍
Then double the amount of floggings and executions.
在电视上直播给他们看
Put them on TV. Broadcast them live.
散播恐惧  让恐惧增长
Sow fear. More fear.
没用的
It won't work.
只要尚存希望  恐惧就不管用
Fear does not work as long as they have hope.
凯妮丝·艾佛丁就是给他们希望的人
And Katniss Everdeen is giving them hope.
她订婚了
She's engaged.
尽可能地报道这一切
Make everything about that.
她会穿什么样的裙子  鞭刑直播
What kind of dress is she gonna wear? Floggings.
婚礼蛋糕是什么样的  死刑直播
What's the cake gonna look like? Executions.
会邀请谁参加  散播恐惧
Who's gonna be there? Fear.
地毯式报道  压死他们
Blanket coverage. Shove it in their faces.
给民众看看  她是我们这边的
Show them that she is one of us now.
他们会恨死她  到时自然会替你杀掉她
They're gonna hate her so much they might just kill her for you.
好主意
Brilliant.
你什么时候...
When did you...
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
我们能逃去哪
Where are we gonna run away?
到树林里  像以前说过的那样
Into the woods. Like we always talked about.
如果现在离开  我们今晚就能远离这里
If we leave right now, we can be far away from here by tonight.
我们是指谁
Yeah, who's "We"?
你和我  还有你的未婚夫
You, me and your fiance?
这不只是我跟皮塔的事了
It's not just me and Peeta any more.
斯诺说要杀了你
Snow threatened to have you killed.
还有谁
Anyone else?
虽然他没直接告诉我
Well, he didn't exactly give me a copy of the list,
但我猜还有咱俩的家人
but a good guess, it includes both of our families.
除非怎样  你跟皮塔结婚?
Unless what? You and Peeta get married?
没有除非
Unless nothing now.
盖尔  我们可以做到的
Gale, we can do it.
在收获节的那天清晨你也说我们可以的
You said yourself that we could do it the morning of the Reaping.
我们现在走吧
What do you say now?
你爱我吗
Do you love me?
盖尔  你知道我对你的感情
Gale, you know how I feel about you.
可是现在我对谁都不会有想法
But I can't think about anyone that way right now.
自从收获节以来
The only thing that I can think about
每一天  每一秒
every day, every waking moment
我都在恐惧中度过
since the Reaping, is how afraid I am.
我没有心思去想别的
There's no room for anything else.
不过  也许离开这里之后
But maybe, if we got away from here,
去安全的地方  情况会不一样
if we went somewhere safe, it could be different.
我也会不一样
I could be different.
你觉得总统只是在吓唬你
You think maybe the President's bluffing?
他不是在吓唬我
He's not bluffing.
从各区情况看  他没有在吓唬我们
Not with what's going on in the districts.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你看到了什么
What did you see?
群众在大街上暴动  放火
There were people fighting in the streets, and fires,
治安警朝他们开枪  可是人们却...
and Peacekeepers were gunning them down, but the people were...
可是人们却什么
What? The people were what?
他们奋起反抗
They were fighting back.
发生了
It's happening.
终于都发生了
It's finally happening.
我就该在竞技场上吃下毒浆果
I should've just eaten the berries in the arena
照计划那样死去
and died like I was supposed to.
那么一切就会恢复正常
Then everything would be back to normal,
所有人都相安无事了
and everyone would be safe.
相安无事又能怎样
Safe for what?
继续挨饿  像奴隶一样干活
To starve? Work like slaves?
在收获节中奉上自己的孩子
Send their kids to the Reaping?
你没有伤害任何人
You haven't hurt people,
凯妮丝  你为大家带来了机会
Katniss. You've given them an opportunity.
只是大家需要鼓起勇气
They just have to be brave enough to take it.
在矿区里已经传开了  他们想要反抗
There's already talk in the mines. People wanna fight.
我们必须离开  盖尔
We have to go, Gale,
在被他们杀掉之前
before they kill us.
他们会杀掉我们的
They Will kill us.
那其他家庭怎么办
What about the other families?
被留下来的人会怎么样
The ones who stay. What happens to them?
他们都对你抱有期望  凯妮丝
People are looking to you, katniss.
我不要他们来指望我
I don't want anyone looking to me.
我帮不了他们
I can't help them.
那你走吧
You do what you want.
我是不会走的
I'm staying here.
瑟莱德指挥官
Commander Thread,
欢迎来到12区
welcome to District 12.
开始工作
Let's get to work.
-前进  继续前进  -跟紧了
- Let's go! Keep moving! - Stay close!
全面搜索
Find and clear.
烧掉所有违禁品
Burn all contraband.
放开我
Let me go!
瑞普
Ripper!
我的眼睛
My eye!
我带你离开这
I'm gonna get you out of here.
不
No!
别碰她  住手
Leave her be! Stop!
不
No!
把他带到广场
In the square.
给
Here.
没错  捂住那里
Yeah, hold that on there.
不
No!
不  快住手
No! No! Stop!
凯妮丝
Katniss!
我没事
It's okay.
你快走  我没事
Just go. It's okay.
滚开
Move.
还想挨鞭子吗
You want another?
来啊
Go ahead.
-滚开  -不  你会后悔开枪的
- Get out of my way! - No, you don't want to shoot her.
信不信我把你也给毙了
How about I shoot both of you?
指挥官  你是新来的
Look, Commander, you're new here.
相信我  我是在帮你
Trust me, I'm trying to help you.
我是海米奇
I'm Haymitch.
还认得她吗  凯妮丝·艾佛丁
You recognize her? Katniss Everdeen.
都城的宠儿
Darling of The Capitol.
她妨碍治安警察执法
She interfered with a Peacekeeper.
她也有犯傻的时候
I never said she was smart.
她也挨过你鞭子了
Look, you already got a couple of lashes in, right?
不能轻放她  她煽动民心
That's not good enough. She's an agitator.
冷静点  冷静点
Easy, easy.
你确定斯诺想看到
Look, You're sure Snow wants
三个冠军死在这里吗
three dead Victors here?
现在就是这个情况
Because that's what we're looking at.
马上要结婚了  却被你弄花了脸
It's bad enough that you marked up her face
这可真够糟糕的
on the eve of the big wedding.
就这样吧  我们也不追究了
Let it go. And we will, too.
好吧
All right.
没问题
Okay.
不过下一次就是行刑队来执行死刑了
But next time, it's the firing squad.
好主意
Excellent idea.
我才不管她是谁
I don't care who she is.
撤离广场
Clear the square!
今晚实行宵禁
You're all under curfew.
谁天黑之后出来  立马枪毙
Anyone out after dark will be shot on sight.
带他们滚
Get 'em outta here.
盖尔受伤了
It's Gale.
把他抬过来
Get him here.
来吧
Here we go.
放松  高一点  再高一点
Really easy. Up. Up.
好了
Okay.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
新上任的治安警长
New Head Peacekeeper.
可不怎么友善
Not entirely peaceful.
没伤到眼睛  不用缝针
Missed your eye. Doesn't need stitches.
拿雪敷一敷
Make a snow coat.
皮塔  去取雪  我去磨草药
Peeta, get the snow. I'll grind the herbs.
这是什么  弄疼他了
What is that? That's hurting him.
他需要打吗啡
He needs morphining.
没事的
It's okay.
妈妈  让我来吧
Mom. No. I'll do it.
老天
Oh, God.
抓住他
Hold him, please.
会好一点
That's better.
小喵妮
Hey, Catnip.
还以为你已经走了呢
Thought you'd be gone by now.
我哪里都不去
I'm not going anywhere.
就待在这  一直给你捣乱
I'm gonna stay right here. Cause all kinds of trouble.
我也是
Me, too.
去休息一下吧  我来照顾他
You wanna get some rest? I can look after him for a while.
我再去给他取点雪
I'm gonna go get him more snow.
眼睛好点没
How's your eye?
不是眼睛的事在困扰着我
It's not my eye that's bothering me.
我们怎能这样活着
How can we live like this?
谁能容忍这样的生活
How can anybody live like this?
确实很糟糕  可是
It's not living, but...
自从上次饥饿游戏起  情况就不一样了
Since the last Games, something is different.
我能察觉到
I can see it.
你看到了什么
What can you see?
希望
Hope.
不管我做什么
You understand that whatever I do
你和妈妈都会受到牵连
comes back to you and Mom.
我不想你们受到伤害
I don't want you to get hurt.
你不用保护我  或者妈妈
You don't have to protect me. Or Mom.
我们和你心连着心
We're with you.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
直播到这就切断了
The broadcast cut out here.
吵架的画面没放出去
Before any of the excitement happened.
-有多少人看到了  -难说
- How many people saw it? - Hard to say.
有5秒钟的延迟  但事情发生得很快
There was a five second delay, but it happened fast.
阻止不了凯妮丝·艾佛丁
If you cannot contain Katniss Everdeen,
我就只能杀了她
then I will have to terminate her.
我明白
I understand that.
而且不止她
And not just her.
她的所有同类也只好都消灭掉
Her entire species has to be eliminated.
她的同类指
Her species, sir?
其他冠军
The other Victors.
因为她  他们都成了威胁
Now, because of her, they all pose a threat.
因为她  他们都以为自己不可战胜
Because of her, they all think they're invincible.
不管你要玩什么游戏
Whatever game you think you're playing,
那些人都不会配合
those out there are not playing it with you.
我们还有法可赢
There's a way we can still win.
总设计师都管这个叫"留一手"
It's what we Gamemakers like to call "A wrinkle."
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
这是第75届饥饿游戏
this is the 75th year of The Hunger Games.
饥饿游戏章程规定
And it was written in the charter of The Games
每隔25届将有1届精英极限赛
that every 25 years, there would be a Quarter Quell
让新一代人不要忘记
to keep fresh for each new generation the memory of
死去的叛党有多么耻辱
those who died in the uprising against The Capitol.
每届精英极限赛
Each Quarter Quell is
都是极富有特色的比赛
distinguished by Games of a special significance.
现在
And now on this the
在这成功镇压叛乱的75周年纪年日
75th anniversary of our defeat of the rebellion,
我们将庆祝第3届精英极限赛开幕
we celebrate the 3rd Quarter Quell
在此提醒各位  即使最强大的力量
as a reminder that even the strongest
也无法推翻都城的统治
cannot overcome the power of The Capitol.
本届精英极限赛中的
On this, the 3rd Quarter Quell Games,
男女贡品将从
the male and female Tributes
每个区现有的
are to be reaped from the
冠军中抽签产生
existing pool of Victors in each district.
不要
No!
他说的是谁
Who does he mean?
冠军都将在收获节现身
Victors shall present themselves on Reaping Day
-无论年纪大小...  -凯妮丝
- regardless of age... - Katniss...
健康状况
...state of health
或者境况如何
or situation.
不要
No.
皮塔
Peeta.
你来了
There she is.
算好账了吗
Finally did the math?
你来干嘛
And you've come to, what?
要我  去死吗
Ask me to... Die?
我来喝酒
I'm here to drink.
我总算有点用了
Finally, something I can help you with.
皮塔早在45分钟前就来这儿
What's it say that Peeta was
求爷爷告奶奶地让我救你一命
here 45 minutes ago begging to save your life
你怎么才出现
and you only just now show up?
所以我们得救他
It means we have to save him.
你永远也配不上他
You could live 100 lifetimes and never deserve that boy.
得了吧  海米奇
Come on, Haymitch.
不使点手段根本就赢不了游戏
Nobody decent ever wins The Games.
根本就没人能赢
Nobody ever wins The Games. Period.
只有幸存者
There are survivors.
没有赢家
There's no winners.
皮塔必须活下来
Peeta has to survive.
我们要不惜一切代价救他
We have to do whatever it takes to save him.
好吧  如果
All right, if...
如果他们叫到他  我会志愿代替他
If they call his name, I'll volunteer in his place.
海米奇  谢谢你
Haymitch, thank you.
但如果他们叫到我  而皮塔志愿代替
But they call my name and Peeta volunteers,
我也没办法
there's nothing I can do.
你可以告诉他生存技巧  像你帮我一样
You can help him in the arena. Like you did for me.
我觉得这次的游戏会有新花样
I think these Games are gonna be different.
我不在乎  尽你所能
I don't care. Do whatever you can.
皮塔必须活下来  不是我
Peeta lives. Not me.
答应我
Promise me.
好吧
Okay.
早该听你的  我们远走高飞
We should've gone when you said.
欢迎
Welcome.
让我们热烈庆祝饥饿游戏
As we celebrate the 75th anniversary
第75周年庆和第3届
and 3rd Quarter Quell
精英极限赛开幕
of The Hunger Games.
按惯例  女士优先
As always, ladies first.
12区的女性贡品
The female Tribute from District 12,
凯妮丝·艾佛丁
Katniss Everdeen.
好极了
Wonderful.
接下来轮到男士了
And now for the men.
12区的男贡品
The male Tribute from District 12.
海米奇·阿伯纳西
Haymitch Abernathy.
-我志愿当贡品  -我不许你这么做
- I volunteer as Tribute. - I can't let you do that.
你阻止不了我
You can't stop me.
-皮塔  -放开
- Peeta. - Let go.
非常好
Very well.
12区的贡品
The Tributes from District 12.
凯妮丝·艾佛丁
Katniss Everdeen
和皮塔·梅尔拉克
and Peeta Mellark.
那么  接下来...
Well, all that remains is...
不要  可是...
Oh, no. But, but, but...
凯妮丝
Katniss!
-我还得告别呢  -凯妮丝
- I get to say goodbye. - Katniss!
新规则  直接上火车
New plan. Straight to the train.
不要  我要告别
No, I have to say goodbye.
凯妮丝
Katniss!
不要
No.
再见
Good bye!
好了
All right.
开始之前  我有个想法
Before we begin, I've had a thought.
是吗
You don't say?
凯妮丝有嘲笑鸟金胸针
Katniss has her gold Mockingjay pin.
我有金发
I have my hair.
你们两个小伙子也得有金子
I'm going to get you two boys something gold.
为什么
Why is that?
标志
A token.
告诉别人我们是一个团队
Show them we are a team.
他们不能只是...
And they can't just...
谢谢你
Thank you.
好了  现在
All right. Now...
一切都变了
Everything will be different,
因为这是精英极限赛
because it's a Quarter Quell.
都城不惜重金打造了
The Capitol has spared no expense.
全新的训练中心
A new training center.
全新的贡品生活区
New Tribute living quarters.
还有独一无二的竞技场
And of course, a very special arena.
但是今年你们将面对的是其他冠军
But this year you'll be facing other Victors.
都城宠儿
Capitol favorites.
聪明  狡猾  技艺超群
Smart, cunning, skilled.
他们都互相认识
And they all know one another.
你们两个是外来人
You two are the outsiders.
我希望你们忘记
I want you guys to forget
自以为知道的所有饥饿游戏生存之道
everything you think you know about The Games.
去年只是儿戏
Last year was child's play.
今年的选手都是经验丰富的杀手
This year, you're dealing with all experienced killers.
好吧  这是什么意思
All right. What does that mean for us?
意味着你们需要结盟
That means you're gonna have to have some allies.
-好  我觉得要是...  -问题不在你
- Okay. I think that if... - You're not the problem.
不
No.
一开始形势就不利于你们
Look, you're starting at a disadvantage.
他们都是多年的老朋友
Most of these people have been friends for years.
那不是大家都来追杀我们
That just puts us higher on their kill list.
你可以固执己见  但我了解这些人
Do it your own way, but I know these people.
一旦单独行动
You go it alone,
他们首先就会把你们赶尽杀绝
their first move is gonna be to hunt you down.
把你们两个都杀掉
Both of you.
凯妮丝  别这样
Katniss, come on.
我们怎么才能彼此信任
How could any of us even trust each other?
不是信任不信任的问题  是活命的问题
It's not about trust. It's about staying alive.
凯什米尔和格罗斯  兄妹  1区
Cashmere and Gloss. Brother and sister. District 1.
他们赢过背靠背游戏  都城宠儿
They won back-to-back Games. Capitol favorites.
有很多赞助人  十分危险
Lots of sponsors. They will be lethal.
另外两位专业选手
And the other half of the Career Pack,
布鲁图和伊诺巴娅
Brutus and Enobaria.
她牙上戴的什么
What's with her teeth?
她把牙磨成了獠牙
She had them filed into
方便撕裂别人的喉咙
fangs so she could rip people's throats out.
不得不说  她很敬业
She's committed. I'll give her that.
韦瑞斯和比蒂
Wiress and Beetee.
打架能力一般  但头脑聪明
Not fighters, but brilliant.
行为诡异  名副其实的科技狂人
And weird. Real tech-savvy.
他曾一次电死6个贡品  一举赢得比赛
He won his Games by electrocuting six Tributes at once.
变体精灵  伪装大师
The Morphlings. Masters of camouflage.
赢得比赛的手段是躲起来
Basically, won their Games
直到其他人死光为止
by hiding until everyone else was dead.
胜出后一直在自我治疗  太专业了
Self-medicating ever since. Which I applaud.
毫无威胁
Not a threat.
菲尼克·奥戴尔是吧
Finnick Odair, right?
是的  他14岁就赢得了比赛
Yes. He won his Games at 14.
有史以来最年轻的冠军
Youngest ever.
-非常谦虚  -开玩笑的吧
- Extremely humble. - You're kidding.
对  开个玩笑  他是只骄傲的公鸡
Yes, I'm kidding. He's a peacock. A total preener.
但他是都城的宠儿  他们很欣赏他
But he's The Capitol darling. They love him here.
帅气  聪明  战斗技能丰富
Charming, smart, and very skilled at combat.
特别擅长水战
Especially in water.
-有什么弱点吗  -有一个  马格斯
- What about weaknesses? - One. Mags.
她志愿代替安妮
She volunteered for Annie.
马格斯是他的导师  抚养他长大
Mags was his mentor and basically raised him.
只要他想设法保护她  就会暴露自己
If he's trying to protect her in any way, it exposes him.
像他那样的人应该知道她挺不过这关
A guy like that has to know she's not gonna make it.
我打赌要是真的遇到紧急情况
I bet when it really comes down to it,
他不会保护她
he won't protect her.
凯妮丝  我只希望她走的时候
Well, Katniss, I just hope when she goes,
能走得快点
she goes quickly.
她人真的不错
She's actually a wonderful lady.
我们怎么到这了
How'd we get here?
凯妮丝
Katniss.
菲尼克
Hello, Finnick.
来块方糖吗
Do you want a sugar cube?
这糖本来是要喂马的
I mean, it's supposed to be for the horses, but...
可谁管得了它们  对吧
I mean, who cares about them, right?
他们吃糖的机会有的是  而你我...
They got years to eat sugar, whereas you and I...
我们要是看到什么甜食  最好抓住别放
Well, if we see something sweet, we better grab it.
不用了  谢谢  但我想哪天
No thanks. But I would love to
借用一下那套行头
borrow that outfit someday.
你穿那套衣服相当恐怖
You look pretty terrifying in that getup.
那套漂亮的小公主裙哪儿去了
What happened to the pretty little girl dresses?
我长大了  穿不下了
I outgrew them.
那倒是
You certainly did.
这极限赛还真无耻
Shame about this Quell thing.
你能在都城赚大钱
Now, you could've made out like a bandit in The Capitol.
珠宝  现金  要什么有什么
Jewels, money, anything you wanted.
我不喜欢珠宝
Well, I don't like jewels
我的钱多得花不完  所以...
and I have more money than I need, so...
那你的钱怎么花
What did you do with all your wealth, anyway?
我这几年已经不玩钱这么俗的东西了
I haven't dealt in anything as common as money in years.
那和你做朋友  得拿什么交换
Then how do people pay for the pleasure of your company?
秘密
With secrets.
你呢  燃烧的女孩
What about you, Girl on Fire?
有没有秘密给我听听
Any secrets worth my time?
我没有秘密
I'm an open book.
我的秘密大家似乎总是
Everybody always seems to
知道得比我还早
know my secrets before I know them myself.
很遗憾  我觉得你说得对
Unfortunately, I think that's true.
很遗憾你不得不取消婚礼
I'm sorry you had to cancel your wedding.
我知道这对你是毁灭性的打击
I know how devastating that must be for you.
祝你愉快
Have a good day.
-皮塔  -菲尼克
- Peeta. - Finnick.
他想怎样
What'd he want?
打听我的秘密
To know all my secrets.
那他得排队才行了
He'll have to get in line.
贡品们  上马车
Tributes, mount up.
这次不用挥手  不用微笑
No waving and smiling, this time.
眼睛直视前方
I want you to look straight ahead
仿佛观众和整个活动都被你踩在脚下一样
as if the audience and this whole event are beneath you.
这应该简单
That should be easy.
准备好后按下这个
Press this when you're ready.
祝你好运
Good luck.
他们来了
Here they come!
12区的贡品  我们的最爱
From District 12. Our favorites.
-是吗  -我的最爱
- Well... - Or my favorite.
火焰出现了  真是不可思议
There it is! Incredible!
着火了
Fire in the house!
凯妮丝  凯妮丝  凯妮丝
Katniss! Katniss! Katniss!
很好  表现得不错
Nice. Way to make friends out there, you two.
谁让我们有最好的老师
Well, we learned from the best.
给你们介绍两位我特别的朋友
I wanna introduce you to some special friends of mine.
11区的希德和查夫
This is Seeder. And Chaff. From District 11.
他很热情
He's very friendly.
不要请他回家  他会喝光你的酒
Don't invite him over. He'll drink up your liquor.
一会见
I'll see you guys soon.
我们边给你卸妆
Let's get some of that makeup
边聊聊其他贡品
off you and talk about these other Tributes.
这些贡品都疯了
These Tributes are crazy.
也不全是  他人很好
No, not all of 'em. He's a good guy.
继续
Carry on.
你们太惊艳了
You guys look amazing.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我的造型师真白痴
My stylist is such an idiot.
7区  木料  树木
District 7. Lumber. Trees.
我真想给她照脸来上一斧子
I'd love to put my ax in her face.
你现在什么感觉
So what do you think?
好像全世界都想和你上床
Now that the whole world wants to sleep with you?
我没觉得全世界....
I don't think that the whole world...
我没跟你说话
I wasn't talking to you.
好吧
Okay.
能帮我拉下拉链吗
Will you unzip?
好的
Yeah.
谢谢  有机会我们再来一回
Thanks. Let's do it again sometime.
谢谢你
Thank you.
乔安娜·梅森  7区
Johanna Mason, District 7.
记住  凯妮丝  今天的目的是结盟
Remember, Katniss, today's about making allies.
我还没一个中意的
So far I'm not overwhelmed by our choices.
可能我们要去掉最不值得信任的人
I guess we just try to figure out who we trust least
再从剩下的人里挑吧
and work our way backwards from there.
摩擦生热  热生火  理论上是
Friction generates heat. Heat generates fire. In theory.
手应该向下移动
You should move your hands downward.
速度加快
And faster, too.
-大力  -总是出奇迹
- A little brute force... -...is always helpful.
谢谢
Thank you.
桌角那边
By the corner of the table.
普鲁塔什吗
Plutarch?
不是  他旁边
No. Next to him.
力场
Force field.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
闪烁的微光
The shimmering.
左上角
Top left hand side.
看
Look.
那边
There.
看到了吗
You see it?
看着像玻璃
Looks like glass.
为的是把我们和他们隔开
To separate us and them.
应该怪我  去年我朝他们射了一箭
Probably my fault. I shot an arrow at them last year.
电磁的
Electromagnetic.
你怎么知道
How can you tell?
很明显吗
Is it obvious or something?
"Is it obvious?"
-有迹象  -看你周围
- They might as well have a sign. - Look around you.
全息图  灯光
All the holograms, the lights,
都在不停地闪烁  为什么
every now and then they flicker. Why?
因为力场吸收了太多能量
Because the force field is taking up too much energy.
任何系统都有缺陷
There's always a flaw in the system.
好漂亮
That's beautiful.
我看到你志愿代替那个小女孩
I saw you volunteer for that young girl.
真勇敢
It was really brave.
普瑞姆是我妹妹
Prim is my sister.
要是你
If you
要是你教我怎么做这样的鱼钩
If you teach me how to make a fishhook like that,
我可以教你怎么打猎
I could teach you how to hunt.
可以
Yes, yes.
你想一起来试试吗
Do you wanna try with me?
好
Okay.
我先来
I'll go first.
好消息
Good news.
至少有一半贡品想和你结盟
At least half the Tributes want you as an ally.
他们看到她射箭了
Well, they saw her shoot.
亲爱的  你随便选吧
Well, sweetheart, you got your pick of the litter.
我想要韦瑞斯和比蒂
I want Wiress and Beetee.
乔安娜叫他们"疯婆""电公"
Johanna calls them "Nuts" And "Volts."
-好  不错  还有谁  -马格斯
- Well, okay, good. Now, who else? - Mags.
那好吧  谁都不选
All right, fine, then no one.
我告诉他们你还在犹豫
I'll tell them you're still making up your mind.
3区  比蒂·拉特尔
District 3. Beetee Latter.
个人评估报告
Report for individual assessment.
皮塔  我们怎么杀死这些人
Peeta, how are we gonna kill these people?
12区  凯妮丝·艾佛丁
District 12. Katniss Everdeen.
个人评估报告
Report for individual assessment.
艾佛丁小姐
Miss Everdeen.
Miss Everdeen!
你有10分钟来展示选择的技能
You have 10 minutes to present your chosen skill.
希尼卡·克莱恩
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you! Thank you!
感谢光临
Thank you for being here tonight
第75届饥饿游戏前夜
on the eve of the 75th Hunger Games!
既是空前
We have never seen anything like this.
也是绝后
And we will never see anything like it again.
因为今夜  就在这个舞台上
Because tonight, on this stage,
施惠国最耀眼的24颗明星
24 of Panem's brightest stars
将争夺最终的桂冠
will vie for the ultimate crown.
今夜将是他们
Tonight will be their
表达思想的最后一次机会
final opportunity to express their thoughts.
我们表达爱意的最后一次机会
Our final opportunity to express our love.
很不幸的
And heartbreakingly,
也是和绝大多数人的诀别了
to say goodbye to all but one.
激动人心的夜晚
What a night.
让我们听听看
Let's hear it.
多么激动人心啊
It's so exciting!
婚纱吗
A wedding dress?
斯诺总统坚持如此  但我做了些改动
President Snow insisted, but I made a few alterations.
你们让整个游戏都变温情了
You two made The Games a family affair.
你们是所有人的兄弟姐妹
You became everyone's brother and sister.
真不知道该如何和你们告别
I don't know how we're going to let you go.
我们并不是主动来的
We're not going by choice.
你们是我们的家人
You are our family.
没人比你们更爱我们
And I don't see how anyone can love us better.
真感人  真感人
So sweet. So sweet.
你还好吗  亲爱的
Are you all right, dear?
-抱歉  -没关系
- I'm sorry. - That's all right.
我停止不住
I just can't stop crying.
天啊  真会有人相信吗
God! Does anybody actually believe this?
很显然  人人都信
Apparently, everybody.
她很棒
She is very good.
冠军们都很愤怒  凯妮丝
These Victors are angry, Katniss.
为了阻止游戏他们什么都说得出
They'll say anything to try and stop The Games.
我建议你也如此
I suggest you do the same.
比蒂
Beetee...
这些年你为施惠国奉献良多
You have contributed so much to Panem over the years.
我都不知道该更留恋哪一个
I don't know who we will miss more.
你还是你的大脑
You or your brain.
如果举办极限赛是人为规定的话
If the Quarter Quell were written into law by men,
那也可以人为取消它
certainly, it can be unwritten.
不错  很有意思的观点
Yes. Interesting concept.
菲尼克
Finnick...
我知道你有话要说给一个不在场的人
I understand that you have a message for somebody out there.
一个特别的人
A special somebody.
我们能听吗
Can we hear it?
我的挚爱
My love,
我的心
you have my heart
永远属于你
for all eternity
如果我死在竞技场上
and if I die in that arena,
我最后的留恋也将是你的唇
my last thought will be of your lips.
今晚我们见证了太多的眼泪
We have seen a lot of tears here tonight.
但乔安娜的眼里没有眼泪
But I see no tears in Johanna's eyes.
乔安娜  你很生气
Johanna, you are angry.
为什么
Tell me why.
没错  我很生气
Well, yes, I'm angry.
我都快气炸了
You know, I'm getting totally screwed over here.
原本的规则是  我若赢了比赛
The deal was that if I win the Hunger Games,
我将安度余生
I get to live the rest of my life in peace.
可是现在  你们要再杀我一次
But now you want to kill me again.
所以我说  哔你们
Well, you know what? *beep* that!
所有的参与者和策划者  哔你们
And *beep* everybody that had anything to do with it!
好吧
All right then.
好厉害的女人
One woman's opinion.
下一个
Who's next?
转过来
All right, turn around.
这对每位参赛者都是坏消息
I know it's a bad break for everyone involved.
弄好了
I think I'm done.
今晚要转圈吗
Will I be twirling tonight?
最后再转
Save it for the end.
还剩一分钟  好了吗
One minute. Is she ready?
凯妮丝
Katniss.
你本来可以成为最美新娘的
You would have been the most beautiful bride.
谢谢
Thank you.
让他们见识一下真正的美女
Let's go show them what real beauty looks like.
再往上点
It has to go more up.
真美  凯妮丝  观众会爱死你的
Pretty, pretty, Katniss, they're going to adore you.
而他们之中有许多赞助人
And there are a lot of sponsors in the audience,
所以  做你自己就好
so of course, just be your usual self.
其实  再高兴点儿就更好了
Actually, be your happier self.
开玩笑吧  穿婚纱
Really? A wedding dress?
斯诺要我穿的
Snow made me wear it.
女士们先生们  有请...
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome...
-你们熟知的...  -让他付出代价
- You know her... - Make him pay for it.
燃烧的女孩
...as the Girl on Fire.
去年饥饿游戏的冠军
The Victor of last year's Hunger Games.
凯妮丝·艾佛丁
Katniss Everdeen!
凯妮丝·艾佛丁  你真是美极了
Katniss Everdeen, you look fabulous. Doesn't she?
我的天啊
My, my!
凯妮丝
Now, Katniss,
今晚
this is
对我们所有人而言
a very big and very emotional night
盛大而又感人
for all of us.
你说呢
Wouldn't you say?
别冲着我哭  凯撒
Don't go crying on me now, Caesar.
我控制不了啊  你了解的
I can't make any promises. You know me.
就算你能我也不会相信你
You know I wouldn't believe you, even if you did.
我喜欢她  燃烧的女孩还真顽皮
I love her! The Girl on Fire is so cheeky.
但是  凯妮丝  说正经的
But, Katniss, on a more serious note.
我们都有些失望
I think we're all here a little disappointed,
或者说非常失望
more than a little disappointed,
因为你的婚礼没有按计划举行
that a certain wedding did not take place.
对不对  各位
Aren't we, folks?
真遗憾  但我猜
Alas. But am I correct in assuming
你本来打算
that this is the gown that
穿着这身衣服参加婚礼的  对不对
you would have worn on that day, yes or no?
对  斯诺总统认为大家会想看看的
Yes, President Snow thought everyone would want to see it.
斯诺总统还是一如既往的正确
Well, President Snow, as usual, was right.
对不对  各位
Was he not, folks?
我喜欢它  我喜欢它
I love it! I love it!
你们喜欢吗
Don't you love it, folks?
太美了  难以置信的美
It's incredible. It's so gorgeous.
能再来一次吗  来吧  来吧  来吧
Will you do us the honor? Please? Please? Please?
天啊
Oh, my God!
Oh, my!
是只鸟
It's a bird.
还有羽毛呢  就像鸟一样
It's got feathers. It's like a bird.
就像...
It's like a...
就像嘲笑鸟
Like a Mockingjay.
你的设计师这次超常发挥了
Your stylist certainly has outdone himself this time, hasn't he?
真是戏剧性的一幕
What the atricality!
秦纳
Cinna!
鞠个躬吧
Take a bow.
皮塔
But, Peeta,
婚礼和结婚的计划都泡汤了吧
the wedding, the marriage, never to be?
其实我们结婚了
Well, actually, we got married.
秘密地
In secret.
秘密婚礼
A secret wedding?
来讲讲吧
All right. Do tell.
-我们希望这份爱能长久  -当然能
- We want our love to be eternal. - Of course.
凯妮丝和我已经比许多人幸运了
You know, Katniss and I, we've been luckier than most.
所以我本来不该有遗憾的
And I wouldn't have any regrets at all
但是...
if it weren't...
If...
但是什么  怎么了
If it weren't for what? What?
但是我们有孩子了
If it weren't for the baby.
这还真是个新闻
All right. This is news!
继续说下去
Let's find out more.
冷静  这对我们所有人都是新闻
Calm down. This is news to all of us.
取消游戏
Call off The Games!
好吧
All right.
-我们...  -停止游戏
- Let's... - Stop The Games!
大家冷静点儿
Everybody, calm down.
这是个伟大的夜晚  非常伟大
It's a great night. A great night.
这对我们所有人都是新闻
This is news to all of us.
好吧  好吧  好吧
All right, all right, all right.
我们会慎重考虑的
We're going to find out what we do about this.
取消游戏
Cancel The Games!
终止游戏
Stop The Games!
他们不会取消游戏的
There's no way they'll cancel. They can't.
说有孩子了真是聪明
Baby bomb was a stroke of genius.
但很不幸  游戏还得继续
Unfortunately, Games are still on.
现在要告别了
This is goodbye, for now.
给你们的礼物
Presents for the boys.
这是什么
What is this?
你的标记  记得吗
Your token. Remember?
我有金头发  凯妮丝有金色徽章
Hair for me. Pin for Katniss.
你有金镯子
Gold bangle for you.
皮塔有这个  我们说过的那个金奖章
And for Peeta, the medallion that we talked about.
谢谢  艾菲
Thank you, Effie.
我们是支队伍
We're a team. Aren't we?
我对我的冠军们无比骄傲
And I'm so proud of my Victors.
无比骄傲
So proud.
你们真是太...
You're so...
你们本应过更好的生活的
Well, you both deserved so much better.
谢谢  艾菲
Thank you, Effie.
真的很抱歉
I am truly sorry.
谢谢  海米奇
Thank you, Haymitch.
谢谢你所做的一切
For everything.
有什么最后的忠告吗
Any last advice?
活下去
Stay alive.
海米奇  等等
Haymitch, wait.
记得我们的约定
Remember our deal.
想方设法让他活着
Do whatever it takes to keep him alive.
向我保证
Promise me.
好的
Okay.
凯妮丝  当你进入竞技场时
Katniss, when you're in the arena,
记住谁才是你真正的敌人
remember who the real enemy is.
我不想和其他人在一起
I don't want to be with anyone else in there.
只和你
Just you.
这是你想要的吗
If that's what you want.
这就是我想要的
That's what I want.
一会儿见
I'll see you soon.
你的追踪器
Your tracker.
看啊  他们手挽着手
Look at this. They're holding hands.
我要他们死
I want them dead.
耐心点儿
Be patient.
别看现在手挽手
They're holding hands now,
等游戏一开始  马上就拼个你死我活
but the minute the gun goes off, it'll be a bloodbath.
根本没工夫策划反抗的事
And the whole idea of revolution will be discredited.
那她那招呢
And the idea of her?
嘲笑鸟那招
The idea of the Mockingjay?
她背叛的盟友越多  射杀的同伴越多
The more allies she betrays, the more friends she kills,
她的本质暴露得也越多
the more she reveals her true self.
只要能让她的照片升起
As long as it ends with her
再来一声炮响纪念她就行
picture in the sky and the sound of cannon.
-会的  -最好如此
- And it shall. - It better.
我们先看着她弄脏双手吧
Let's watch her get her hands dirty first.
我得走了
Excuse me.
开始吧
Let's start.
这外衣很轻  不保暖
This suit is light. No thermal.
所以我猜场景是热带或沙漠地区
So I'd guess tropics or desert.
倒计时六十秒
Sixty seconds to launch.
那件婚纱真美
That dress was beautiful.
它是你最完美的作品吧
I think it was the best one you've ever made.
我就知道你喜欢
I thought you'd like it.
我只想说  因为我没有...
I just wanted to tell you, because I don't...
打住
Stop.
记住  我仍然赌你赢  燃烧的女孩
Remember, I'm still betting on you, Girl on Fire.
倒计时十秒
Ten seconds to launch.
不
No!
秦纳  不
Cinna! No!
不  不  不
No! No! No!
不  秦纳
No! Cinna!
不  不
No! No!
不
No!
不  不...
No, no...
第七十五届饥饿游戏开始
Let the 75th Hunger Games begin.
祝你们好运
May the odds be ever in your favor.
皮塔
Peeta?
十  九  八
Ten, nine, eight,
七  六
seven, six,
五  四
five, four,
三  二
three, two,
一
One
幸好我们是同盟
Good thing we're allies, right?
镯子哪儿来的
Where did you get that?
你猜呢
Where do you think?
趴下
Duck.
不要信任一区二区的
Don't trust 1 and 2.
我负责这边  你拖住他们
I'll take this side. You hold them off.
我去找皮塔
I'll go find Peeta.
凯妮丝  马格斯找到他了  他在那边
Katniss, Mags found him. He's over here.
凯妮丝  凯妮丝  快跑  快跑
Katniss, Katniss, go, go, go, go.
好了  停一下  停一下
Okay, hold up. Hold up.
到这边来
Here you go.
都没事吧
Okay. You all right now?
没事吧
Okay?
天啊  真热
God, it's hot.
我们必须找到淡水
We gotta find fresh water.
看来不能手挽手了
Well, I guess we're not holding hands any more.
你觉得好笑吗
You think that's funny?
每次炮声响起时  我都觉得无比悦耳
Every time that cannon goes off, it's music to my ears.
我才不关心他们呢
I don't care about any of them.
听你这么说真好
Good to hear.
你想独自面对卡瑞尔一伙那帮人吗
Want to face the Career Pack alone?
海米奇会怎么说
What would Haymitch say?
海米奇又不在
Haymitch isn't here.
我们往前走吧
Let's keep moving.
皮塔  不
Peeta, no!
皮塔
Peeta?
他没有呼吸了  他没有呼吸了
He's not breathing. He's not breathing.
他没有呼吸了  皮塔
He's not breathing! Peeta!
皮塔
Peeta?
醒醒  醒醒
Come on! Come on!
求你了  醒过来
Please, wake up.
不
No.
求你了  醒过来
Please, wake up.
-醒醒  -醒醒
- Come on. - Come on!
镜头拉近
Bring me in closer.
大炮就位
Cannon ready?
醒醒  醒醒  醒醒  皮塔
Come on. Come on. Come on, Peeta!
求你了  皮塔  皮塔
Please, Peeta. Peeta.
醒醒
Come on.
皮塔  皮塔
Peeta? Peeta.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
小心  那边有力场
Be careful. There's a force field up there.
天啊  你刚才死了
Oh, my God. You were dead.
你刚才死了  心脏都不跳了
You were dead. Your heart stopped.
没事了
It's okay.
现在又跳了
It's working now.
-你...你想站起来吗  -好的
- You... Do you wanna stand up? - Yeah.
没事的
It's okay.
我希望我也能这样爱一个人
Someday I want to love someone that much.
你会的  宝贝  你会的
And so you shall, my darling. So you shall.
稍等
Hang on.
那个力场...
The force field...
是个穹顶  我们在竞技场边缘
It's a dome. We're at the edge of the arena.
没有任何淡水的迹象
We couldn't find any signs of fresh water.
天快黑了
It's gonna get dark soon.
背后没人就不会有危险
We'll be safe with our backs protected.
我们应该驻扎下来  轮流守夜
We should set up camp. Take turns sleeping.
我来值第一班
I can take first watch.
不行
Not a chance.
亲爱的  还记得我刚刚为皮塔做的事吗
Honey, that thing I did back there for Peeta?
那叫"救他的命"
That was called "Saving his life."
要是我想杀你们的话  我早下手了
If I wanted to kill either of you, I would've done it by now.
为什么不去休息一下  我来值第一班
Why don't you get some rest? I'll take the first watch.
就一会儿
Just for a little bit.
皮塔怎么样了
How's Peeta?
我想他没事了
He's okay, I think.
和我们一样有点脱水
Just dehydrated like the rest of us.
八个
Eight.
喝个痛快
Drink up?
什么东西
What is it?
是海米奇给我们的
It's from Haymitch.
我想是个木龙头
I think it's a spile.
什么
A What?
我的天啊  我的天啊
You're kidding me. You're kidding me.
来喝点儿吧
Get some water.
我去拿片叶子
I'm gonna get a leaf.
我给马格斯拿些过去
I'll get some for Mags.
来吧
There we go.
再喝点儿吗
Want some more?
十二下
I counted 12.
代表午夜吗
Midnight?
或者代表十二个区
Or the number of districts.
那个
Well...
你要是不睡  我就去睡了
If you're not gonna sleep, I will.
好的
Okay.
快跑  快跑  这雾有毒
Run! Run! The fog is poison!
快  快  快
Come on, come on, come on
好了
There!
天啊  天啊
God! God!
马格斯  快  快  快跑  快跑
Mags, please, please! Come on! Come on!
皮塔
Peeta.
我拖不动他
I can't carry him.
皮塔  求你了
Peeta, please.
皮塔  求你了  站起来  快跑
Peeta, please, stand up. We have to go.
马格斯
Mags?
-马格斯  马格斯  -菲尼克
- Mags? Mags! - Finnick.
-马格斯  -菲尼克
- Mags! - Finnick.
马格斯
Mags!
菲尼克  菲尼克  我们得走了
Finnick! Finnick, we have to go.
我们得离开这里
We have to get outta here.
我们得走了
We have to go.
好吧  快走  快走  快走
All right, come on, come on. Come on.
好的
Okay.
该死
Shit!
水  水能疗伤
The water! The water helps.
我们需要武器
We need our weapons.
马格斯的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about Mags.
她本来也撑不到最后的
She was never gonna make it.
所以
So...
怎么
What?
-皮塔  -怎么
- Peeta. - Yeah?
慢慢走过来
Walk over here slowly.
去沙滩
Get to the beach.
向沙滩跑
We gotta get to the beach!
这是谁
Who is that?
变体精灵  帮我扶她一把
A Morphling! Help me get her!
嘿  没事了
Hey, hey, hey. It's okay. It's okay.
这才叫美景呢  看上面
Hey, you wanna see something? Look up. Look.
看哪
Look at it. Look at that.
不可思议  是吗
It's incredible, isn't it?
绚烂多彩
All those colors.
什么都不要想
Don't worry about anything else.
我在你身边
I'll be right here with you.
没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
她为我而死  我都不知道她的名字
She sacrificed herself for me and I didn't even know her name.
你觉得她是为你牺牲的
You think she sacrificed herself?
至少看起来如此
Looked like it.
没道理啊
That doesn't make any sense.
瞧啊  送给你
Look. For you.
谢谢
Thank you.
这倒新鲜
That's new.
那里有人
Someone's here.
乔安娜
Johanna?
-乔安娜  -菲尼克
- Johanna! - Finnick!
又来了几个盟友
Guess we have more allies.
总得来说
Well...
我救了他们
I got 'em out.
我们都在丛林深处
We were all the way deep into
我以为那里安全些
the jungle where I thought it was gonna be safe.
紧接着下起了雨
That's when the rain started.
我以为那是水
I thought it was water.
结果是血
It turned out to be blood.
-滴答  -浓浓的鲜血
- Tick took. - Hot, thick blood.
-瓢泼而下  -滴答
- It was coming down. - Tick took.
差点呛死
It was choking us.
我们困在那里呕吐不止  什么也看不到
We were stumbling around, gagging on it, blind.
滴答
Tick took.
-就在这时布莱特撞到了力场  -滴答
- That's when Blight hit the force field. - Tick took.
滴答
Tick took.
虽然不咋地  但是有家的气息
It wasn't much, but it was from home.
滴答
Tick took.
-滴答  -她怎么了
- Tick took. - What's wrong with her?
-吓到了  -滴答
- She's in shock. - Tick took.
脱水加重了症状  你们有淡水喝吗
Dehydration isn't helping. Do you have fresh water?
-能弄来点  -你
- We can get some. - Just...
滴答
Tick took.
别这样了
Listen. Stop it!
-放开她  -坐下
- Hey! Lay off her! - Just sit down!
你干什么
Hey! What are you doing?
我是为了你才救他们出来的
I got them out for you!
没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
放开我  菲尼克
Let me go, Finnick!
-为了我  什么意思  -放开我
- For me? What does that mean? - Let me go.
-你是找他们当盟友来着  -我没事
- You did want them as allies. - I'm fine.
来  我们去洗洗
Come on, let's get you cleaned up.
滴答
Tick took.
-滴答  -滴答
- Tick took. - Tick took!
滴答  好吧
Tick took, okay.
比蒂拿的是什么
What does Beetee have there?
线盘吗  一种电线
The coil? It's some kind of wire.
从宙斯之角拿的吗
Did he get it from the Cornucopia?
为了拿它背上还挨了一刀呢
Took a knife in the back to get it.
-滴答  滴答  -够了
- Tick took! Tick took! - All right.
我没法
I can't.
你  自己和疯子疯去吧
Just... Have fun with "Nuts."
滴答
Tick took.
是表
It's a clock.
这是个表盘
表盘  韦瑞斯  你真是个天才
My God, it's a clock! Wiress, you're a genius.
你真是个天才
You're a genius!
竞技场设计成表盘状
This entire arena seems to be
每小时出现一次新危机
laid out like a clock with a new threat every hour,
但都只存在于一定的区域内
but they stay only within their wedge.
闪电是第一次
It all starts with the lightning,
然后是血雨  毒雾  猿猴
then the blood rain, fog, monkeys.
前四个小时是这些
That's the first four hours.
那个巨浪是从10点打过来的
At 10, that big wave hits from over there.
韦瑞斯  你是个天才
Wiress, you're a genius.
转盘尾部指向12
Look, the tail points to 12.
就是闪电开始的时间  正午和零点
That's where the lightning strikes at noon and midnight.
-打在哪里  -那棵巨树
- Strikes where? - That big tree.
很好
Good.
滴答滴答滴  老鼠上钟台
"Hickory dickory dock. The mouse ran up the clock.
一下是一点  老鼠下钟台
"The clock struck one, the mouse ran down.
滴答滴答滴
"Hickory dickory dock."
零点到一点  闪电
So 12:00 to 1:00, lightning.
一点到两点  血雨
And 1:00 to 2:00 is blood.
接着是毒雾和猿猴
Then fog. And then monkeys.
滴答滴答滴  狗儿向钟吠
"Hickory dickory dock. The dog barked at the clock.
三下是三点
"The clock struck 3:00..."
十点到十一点  巨浪
And then 10:00 to 11:00, the wave.
其他时间呢  你们都见到什么了
What about everything else? Did you guys see anything?
滴答滴答滴
"Hickory dickory dock."
-只见到了血雨  -无所谓是什么
- Nothing but blood. - It doesn't matter.
只要我们避开
As long as we steer clear
有危险的区域就安全了
of whichever sector is active, we'll be safe.
嗯  虽然只是相对安全
Yeah. Relatively speaking.
转换模式  让转盘转起来
Change it up. Spin it.
抓紧
Hold on!
不要
No!
好了  够了
Okay. That's enough.
看他们怎么确定时刻
Let's see how they tell time now.
你没事吧
You Okay?
拿上必需品  离开这倒霉的岛
Let's just get what we need and get off the bloody island.
除了布鲁图和伊诺巴娅  还有谁活着
So besides Brutus and Enobaria, who's left?
查夫应该也没死
Maybe Chaff.
-就他们仨了  -他们知道我们人多
- Just those three. - They know they're outnumbered.
应该不会再来袭击了
I doubt they'll attack again.
在沙滩上我们就是安全的
We're safe here on the beach.
我们怎么办  追杀他们吗
So what do we do? We hunt 'em down?
凯妮丝  救救我
Katniss, help me!
普瑞姆
Prim!
-普瑞姆  普瑞姆  -不行
- Prim! Prim! - No!
凯妮丝  凯妮丝  等等
Katniss! Katniss, wait!
普瑞姆  普瑞姆
Prim! Prim!
普瑞姆
Prim!
凯妮丝
Katniss!
救我  救救我
Help me! Help me!
凯妮丝
Katniss!
-你没事吧  -菲尼克
- You okay? - Finnick!
菲尼克
Finnick!
-别去  不是她  -安妮
- No! It's not her. - Annie!
安妮
Annie!
安妮  安妮
Annie! Annie!
菲尼克  那不是她
Finnick! It's not her.
是学舌鸟  不是她
It's just a jabberjay. It's not her.
你觉得它们怎么会她的声音的
Well, how do you think they got that sound?
-得有模本学舌鸟才能学  -凯妮丝
- Jabberjays copy. - Katniss!
盖尔
Gale.
快跑
Come on, come on, come on!
皮塔
Peeta!
停下  没事的
Stop, stop, stop! It's okay!
没事了  只是幻觉  不是真的
It's okay! They're just mutts! It's not real!
过去了  没事了  它们走了
It's over. It's okay. They're gone.
时刻结束了  没事了
The hour's gone. The hour's up. It's all right.
普瑞姆  她在哪
Prim! Find Prim!
不要动  普瑞姆没事
No, no. Prim's okay.
-你还好吗  -我没事
- Are you okay? - Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine.
他们不会伤害普瑞姆的
Okay? They won't touch Prim. All right?
你未婚夫是对的  民众喜欢你妹妹
Your fiance's right. The whole country loves your sister.
他们要敢折磨她  哪怕碰她一根手指头
If they tortured her or did anything to her,
别说十二区不容他们
forget the districts,
都城人自己都会暴动
there would be riots in the damn Capitol.
听到了吗  斯诺
Hey, how does that sound, Snow?
让你尝尝后院起火的滋味
What if we set your backyard on fire?
你总不能把所有人都关到这吧
You know, you can't put everybody in here.
怎么啦
What?
他们没法要挟我
They can't hurt me.
我在乎的人都不在了
There's no one left that I love.
我去给你弄点水
I'll get you some water.
谢谢
Thank you.
安妮是谁
Who's Annie?
安妮·克莱斯塔  马格斯志愿替代的人
Annie Cresta. The girl Mags volunteered for.
她是四  五年前的冠军
She won, like, four years... five years ago.
她就是那个有点
Is she the one that went a little...
爱情难以捉摸
Love is weird.
我有个想法
I have a plan.
菲尼克
Finnick!
我有个想法
I have a plan.
对卡瑞尔来说  难道丛林更安全吗
Where do the Careers feel safest? The jungle?
丛林就是噩梦
The jungle's a nightmare.
应该是沙滩
Probably here on the beach.
但他们却没来
Then why are they not here?
因为我们在这  我们守住了这里
Because we are. We claimed it.
要是我们离开  他们就会来
And if we left, they would come.
或者至少躲在边界
Or stay hidden in the tree line.
四个小时后
Which in just over four hours
十点的巨浪就会打到那
will be soaked with water from the 10:00 wave.
而到了午夜
And what happens at midnight?
-闪电会击中那棵巨树  -我的计划是
- Lightning strikes that tree. - Here's what I propose.
我们在黄昏时离开沙滩  去闪电的落点
We leave the beach at dusk. We head to the lightning tree.
让他们回沙滩
That should draw them back to the beach.
快午夜时
Prior to midnight
我们把线从树上引到水里
we then run this wire from the tree to the water.
所有在水里或者湿沙上的人都会被烤焦
Anyone in the water or on the damp sand will be electrocuted.
万一电线烧断了呢
How do we know the wire's not gonna burn up?
不会  因为是我发明的
Because I invented it.
我保证不会烧断
I assure you, it won't burn up.
这确实比追踪他们容易
Well, it's better than hunting them down.
有何不可呢
Yeah, why not?
就算失败也没什么损失
If it fails, no harm done anyway, right?
好吧  就这么干
All right, I say we try it.
我们要怎么帮忙
So what can we do to help?
接下来的六个小时里保护好我
Keep me alive for the next six hours.
就帮了很大的忙了
That would be extremely helpful.
我们得离开他们
I think we need to go.
计划会成功的
This plan's gonna work.
我也这么想
I think so, too.
你我都很清楚卡瑞尔死后的局面
And once the Careers are dead, we both know what happens next.
我不想先反目
I don't want to be the one that shoots first.
要是他们也不想呢
What if they don't either?
要是我们都不动手呢
What if all of us refuse to shoot first?
我们还是会死
We might still end up dead.
也许不会  上次就成功了
Maybe not. I mean, it worked for us last time.
他们不会犯同样的错误
They're not gonna make that same mistake again.
你我都清楚只有一个人能活着离开
You know and I know there's only one person walking out of here.
我们俩只能活一个
And it's gonna be one of us.
卡瑞尔还活着
The Careers are still out there.
我们至少应该和他们一起待到午夜
We should stick with these guys till midnight.
只要听到炮响  我们就离开
And if we hear a cannon, we go.
凯妮丝  我不知道你和
Katniss, I don't know what kinda deals
海米奇怎么约定的
you made with Haymitch.
但他也让我保证了
but he made me promises, too.
就算是你死我活
If you die and I live,
我也一无所有
I'd have nothing.
我没有其他在乎的人了
Nobody else that I care about.
皮塔
Peeta.
但你不同
It's different for you.
你的家人需要你
Your family needs you.
你必须活下去
You have to live,
为了他们活着
for them.
那你呢
What about you?
没人需要我
Nobody needs me.
我需要你
I do.
真的
I need you.
好了  鸳鸯们
All right, lovebirds!
她已经做好了战斗的准备
She is preparing to fight.
这才是好姑娘
That's our girl.
正应了你的预测
This is what you predicted.
仔细设计每一步
Moves and countermoves.
没错
Indeed.
完事了来一杯吧
We'll toast when it's done?
尽情享受吧
In the meantime, make yourself comfortable.
最小炭化度
Minimal charring.
十分难得的导体
It's an impressive conductor.
计划开始
Let's get started.
一般来说
Typically a lightning
一次闪电可携带50亿焦耳能量
strike contains five billion joules of energy.
所以闪电落下时不能留在附近
We don't want to be anywhere in the vicinity when this hits.
两个姑娘先离开
You two girls, go together now.
带着这个  解开时要小心
Take this. Unspool it carefully.
要确保整个线盘都在水里  懂吗
Make sure the entire coil is in the water. You understand?
然后在巨树两点方向和我们会合
Then head to the tree at the 2:00 sector. We'll meet you there.
我一起去  保护她们
I'm gonna go with them as a guard.
不用  你得在这保护我
No,no,no. You're staying here to protect me.
还有树
And the tree.
我得跟着她
No, I need to go with her.
还有两个卡瑞尔活着  我需要两个保镖
There are two Careers out there. I need two guards.
菲尼克一个人也能保护好你
Finnick can protect you just fine on his own.
要不让菲尼克和乔安娜留下
Why can't Finnick and Johanna
我和皮塔去放线盘
stay with you and Peeta and I'll take the coil?
你们保证过要确保我活过午夜不是吗
You all agreed to keep me alive till midnight, correct?
这是他的计划  我们都同意了的
It's his plan. We all agreed to it.
有问题
Is there a problem here?
好问题
Excellent question.
没问题
No. There's no problem.
午夜见
I'll see you at midnight.
好吧  出发
All right, let's go!
快点
Come on.
我现在
I want to put as much
想离沙滩越远越好
distance between me and this beach as possible.
我可不想被烤焦
Frying is not how I want to go.
有动静
There's something...
别起来
Stay down.
这边
Come on.
乔安娜  你在哪
Johanna, where are you?
乔安娜
Johanna?
皮塔
Peeta.
比蒂  比蒂
Beetee. Beetee!
皮塔
Peeta!
凯妮丝  你在哪
Katniss, where are you?
松手吧  艾佛丁小姐
Let it fly, Miss Everdeen.
松手
Let it fly.
凯妮丝
Katniss.
别忘了敌人是谁
Remember who the real enemy is.
凯妮丝  快离开巨树
Katniss, get away from that tree!
凯妮丝  离开巨树
怎么可能
It's not possible.
海文斯比
Heavensbee!
普鲁塔什·海文斯比
Plutarch Heavensbee!
长官  停电了
Sir, we've lost power.
要是知道了那男孩的事她会崩溃的
She's gonna lose it when she finds out about the boy.
但她还是会合作吧
She'll still cooperate, though?
皮塔不在了可真不一定
Without Peeta? There's no guarantee.
到时候再告诉她
Just tell her when...
早上好  甜心
Morning, sweetheart.
你怎么和他们在一起
What are you doing with them?
你就打算用个注射器反抗都城
You and a syringe against The Capitol?
所以才不让你参与计划
See, this is why no one lets you make the plans.
-你到底在这干什么  -住手
- What the hell are you doing in here? - Stop.
住手  听好
Stop. Just listen.
在斯诺的监视下我们没法告诉你实情
We couldn't tell you with Snow watching.
太危险
It was too risky.
你知道的越少越好
Better for you to know nothing.
皮塔在哪
Where's Peeta?
凯妮丝
Now, Katniss...
从一开始就是为你而来
You have been our mission from the beginning.
我们一直在想法救你出来
The plan was always to get you out.
一半的贡品都参与了
Half the Tributes were in on it.
这是场革命  你就是我们的嘲笑鸟
This is the revolution. And you are the Mockingjay.
现在我们在去13区的路上
And we're on our way to District 13 right now.
13区
13?
没错
13. Yes.
皮塔在哪
Where's Peeta?
他的追踪器还在  乔安娜取出了你的
He still has his tracker in his arm. Johanna cut yours out.
他在哪
Where is he?
还在都城
In The Capitol.
他们抓了他和乔安娜
They got him and Johanna.
你混蛋  你个
You son of a bitch! You son of a...
你保证要先救他的
You promised me that you would save him over me!
你保证了的  你这个骗子
You promised me! You're a liar. You're a liar.
醒了  小喵妮
Hey, Catnip.
你没事了
You're okay.
只是睡了几天
You've just been asleep for a few days.
我们到家了吗
Are we home?
盖尔
Gale?
普瑞姆呢
Where's Prim?
她还好
She's alive.
你妈妈也没事  我及时救她们出来了
So is your mother. I got 'em out in time.
救出来是什么意思
Got them out?
游戏结束后  他们的飞行器就来了
After The Games, they sent in hovercrafts.
丢下了无数燃烧弹
And they started dropping firebombs.
她们不在12区了
They're not in 12?
没有12区了
There is no District 12.
一切都不复存在了
It's all gone.
饥饿游戏2：星火燎原